<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE tmx SYSTEM "tmx11.dtd">
<tmx version="1.1">
  <header creationtool="OmegaT" o-tmf="OmegaT TMX" adminlang="EN-US" datatype="plaintext" creationtoolversion="5.7.1_0_c3206253" segtype="sentence" srclang="en"/>
  <body>
<!-- Default translations -->
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>A closer look at it will reveal the impact of Gaugin and other Impressionists of the time such as Monet – the colors and the blurry and flowing nature of the objects, the bright light, and very short brush strokes.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="dinag" changedate="20230523T095217Z" creationid="dinag" creationdate="20230523T095217Z">
        <seg>Una mirada más atenta revelará el impacto de Gaugin y otros impresionistas de la época, como Monet: los colores y la naturaleza borrosa y fluida de los objetos, la luz brillante y las pinceladas muy cortas.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>A good example is the painting called “The Potato Eaters” which was created in 1885 and brought much recognition to the artist.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="dinag" changedate="20230522T211955Z" creationid="dinag" creationdate="20230522T211955Z">
        <seg>Un buen ejemplo es el cuadro llamado "Los comedores de patatas" que fue creado en 1885 y trajo mucho reconocimiento al artista.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>A historical study began to explore Van Gogh’s depression and his artistic production throughout his close relationship with Gauguin, another artist of his time.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="OmegaT Aligner" changedate="20230511T161419Z" creationid="OmegaT Aligner" creationdate="20230511T161419Z">
        <seg>Un estudio histórico comenzó a explorar la depresión de Van Gogh y su producción artística a lo largo de su estrecha relación con Gauguin, otro artista de su época.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Abstract</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="dinag" changedate="20230522T133712Z" creationid="dinag" creationdate="20230522T133712Z">
        <seg>Resumen</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>According to Gayford (2008), in May 1888, Van Gogh decided to rent the right-hand part of the house.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="maria" changedate="20230522T180616Z" creationid="maria" creationdate="20230522T180616Z">
        <seg>Según Gayford (2008), en mayo de 1888, Van Gogh decidió alquilar la parte derecha de la casa.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>After Gauguin and Van Gogh agreed to work together, they traveled to the south of France, and bought the yellow house in Arles in early 1888, in the Provence section of France, and began working on the house (Naifeh &amp; Smith, 2011).</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="dinag" changedate="20230523T100154Z" creationid="dinag" creationdate="20230523T100154Z">
        <seg>Después de que Gauguin y Van Gogh acordaron trabajar juntos, viajaron al sur de Francia y compraron la casa amarilla de Arlés a principios de 1888, en la Provenza francesa, y empezaron a trabajar en ella (Naifeh y Smith, 2011). </seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>After Gauguin finally left, Van Gogh cut off a part of his ear.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="maria" changedate="20230511T155121Z" creationid="maria" creationdate="20230511T155121Z">
        <seg>Después de que Gauguin finalmente abadonara, Van Gogh se amputó parte de la oreja .</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>After many cooperative efforts by both artists, problems soon arose due to basic differences in their personalities.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="OmegaT Aligner" changedate="20230511T161419Z" creationid="OmegaT Aligner" creationdate="20230511T161419Z">
        <seg>Tras muchos esfuerzos de cooperación por parte de ambos artistas, pronto surgieron problemas debido a diferencias básicas en sus personalidades.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>After that, he was home tutored with his sister for a while before he joined the Jan Provily’s boarding school at Zevenbergen.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="dinag" changedate="20230522T212649Z" creationid="dinag" creationdate="20230522T212649Z">
        <seg>Después, recibió clases particulares en casa de su hermana durante un tiempo antes de ingresar en el internado de Jan Provily en Zevenbergen.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Although Vincent Van Gogh died young, he was a prolific painter, and his life of probable mental illness and unsuccessful relationships is of interest to this writer, who is studying to become an art therapist.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="dinag" changedate="20230511T211014Z" creationid="dinag" creationdate="20230511T211014Z">
        <seg>A pesar de que Vincent Van Gogh muriera jóven, él fue un pintor prodigioso, y su vida de enfermedades mentales y relaciones fallidas es el interés para este autor, el cual estudia para convertirse en un arteterapeuta.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Although the eleven seceding states tried to form their own country, the power of the Union was too strong and the United States remained as one nation (Keegan, 2010).</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="paula" changedate="20230519T182203Z" creationid="paula" creationdate="20230519T182203Z">
        <seg>Aunque los once estados secesionistas intentaron formar su propio país, el poder de la Unión era demasiado fuerte y Estados Unidos permaneció como una sola nación (Keegan, 2010).</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Although the war took place in the United States in North America, the events in America influenced life in Europe since the union decided to blockade the Confederate seaports which supplied cotton and other material into Europe.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="OmegaT Aligner" changedate="20230507T173348Z" creationid="OmegaT Aligner" creationdate="20230507T173348Z">
        <seg>Aunque la guerra tuvo lugar en Estados Unidos, en Norteamérica, los acontecimientos en América influyeron en la vida en Europa, ya que la unión decidió bloquear los puertos marítimos confederados que suministraban algodón y otros materiales a Europa.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>American Civil War</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="OmegaT Aligner" changedate="20230507T173348Z" creationid="OmegaT Aligner" creationdate="20230507T173348Z">
        <seg>Guerra Civil Americana</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>And you may take as long as you wish.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="maria" changedate="20230522T121837Z" creationid="maria" creationdate="20230522T121837Z">
        <seg>Y puedes tomarte todo el tiempo que quieras.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Art therapy</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="maria" changedate="20230522T120532Z" creationid="maria" creationdate="20230522T120532Z">
        <seg>Terapia artística</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>As a concept, depression is divided into a common feeling such as “blues” or “sadness” and clinical depression that requires medical treatment and the help of a professional.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="paula" changedate="20230521T134730Z" creationid="paula" creationdate="20230521T134730Z">
        <seg>Como concepto, la depresión se divide en un sentimiento común como el "blues" o la "tristeza" y la depresión clínica que requiere tratamiento médico y la ayuda de un profesional.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>As a result, Gogh was locked up without books, paintings, or even his pipe.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="paula" changedate="20230521T161306Z" creationid="paula" creationdate="20230521T161306Z">
        <seg>Como consecuencia, Gogh fue encerrado sin libros, cuadros, ni siquiera su pipa.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>As a result, he developed emotional and mental difficulties.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="maria" changedate="20230522T115053Z" creationid="maria" creationdate="20230522T115053Z">
        <seg>Como resultado, desarrolló dificultades emocionales y mentales.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>As a saying goes, “morning shows the day”, which means if the beginning is good, then the result will also be good, so it was with Vincent Van Gogh ‘s talent.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="dinag" changedate="20230511T202337Z" creationid="dinag" creationdate="20230511T202337Z">
        <seg>Como dice el dicho &lt;&lt; lo que bien empieza, bien acaba&gt;&gt; que significa si el comienzo es bueno, entonces el resultado también lo será, y así fue con el talento de Vincent Van Gogh.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>As an example, the examiner can ask if an individual has drawn a familiar or just an abstract person, how he or she feels about the tree in the picture, what house is associated with the one drawn on the sheet of paper, and so on.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="maria" changedate="20230522T174958Z" creationid="maria" creationdate="20230522T174958Z">
        <seg>Por ejemplo, el examinador puede preguntar al individuo si ha dibujado a una persona conocida o sólo abstracta, qué le parece el árbol del dibujo, qué casa se asocia con la dibujada en la hoja de papel, etcétera.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>As can be seen in the painting, this part of the building looks different than any other – it has green shutters on the windows, which is why it contrasts with the rest of the picture.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="maria" changedate="20230522T180809Z" creationid="maria" creationdate="20230522T180809Z">
        <seg>Como puede verse en el cuadro, esta parte del edificio tiene un aspecto diferente a las demás: tiene contraventanas verdes en las ventanas, por lo que contrasta con el resto del cuadro.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>As for Van Gogh’s painting, first of all, he drew the house he once lived in.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="maria" changedate="20230522T180448Z" creationid="maria" creationdate="20230522T180448Z">
        <seg>En cuanto al cuadro de Van Gogh, en primer lugar, dibujó la casa en la que vivió una vez.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>As for the environmental causes of depression, they are numerous.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="paula" changedate="20230521T140314Z" creationid="paula" creationdate="20230521T140314Z">
        <seg>En cuanto a las causas ambientales de la depresión, son numerosas.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>As mentioned in the book “The letters of Vincent Van Gogh” (Van Gogh &amp; Leeuw, 1997), Vincent Van Gogh himself reflected on his abrupt withdrawal from school, as he wrote to his older brother Theo that “My youth was gloomy and cold and sterile” (Naifeh &amp; Smith, 2011, p.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="dinag" changedate="20230522T212831Z" creationid="dinag" creationdate="20230522T212831Z">
        <seg>Como se menciona en el libro "Las cartas de Vincent Van Gogh" (Van Gogh &amp; Leeuw, 1997), el propio Vincent Van Gogh reflexionó sobre su abrupto abandono de la escuela, ya que escribió a su hermano mayor Theo que "Mi juventud fue sombría y fría y estéril" (Naifeh &amp; Smith, 2011, p.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>As the Prussian war approached, Manet joined the army and moved his family away from Paris.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="paula" changedate="20230519T191439Z" creationid="paula" creationdate="20230519T191439Z">
        <seg>Al acercarse la guerra prusiana, Manet se alistó en el ejército y trasladó a su familia lejos de París.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>As the war progressed and more territory fell into the power of Union, the blockade became an international issue.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="OmegaT Aligner" changedate="20230507T173348Z" creationid="OmegaT Aligner" creationdate="20230507T173348Z">
        <seg>A medida que la guerra avanzaba y más territorio caía en poder de la Unión, el bloqueo se convirtió en un problema internacional.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>At Saint-Remy, Van Gogh was extremely productive; it can be concluded that working on his paintings was bringing him relief.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="maria" changedate="20230511T155702Z" creationid="maria" creationdate="20230511T155702Z">
        <seg>En Saint-Rémy, Van Gogh fue extremadamente productivo; se puede concluir que pintar sus cuadros lo aliviaba.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Before passing the test, a person is provided with three separate sheets of paper with words a house, a tree, and a person written on them (Knoff, 2003, p.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="maria" changedate="20230522T121432Z" creationid="maria" creationdate="20230522T121432Z">
        <seg>Antes de pasar la prueba, la persona recibe tres hojas de papel con las palabras "casa", "árbol" y "persona" escritas en ellas (Knoff, 2003, p.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Besides, Van Gogh experienced seizures that were caused by temporal lobe epilepsy, according to his doctors.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="dinag" changedate="20230522T211502Z" creationid="dinag" creationdate="20230522T211502Z">
        <seg>Además, Van Gogh sufría convulsiones causadas por epilepsia del lóbulo temporal, según sus médicos.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Besides, Van Gogh had a lot in common with Lautrec – they both were deeply moved by the Japanese of art with its thin and curvy lines, and complex figures.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="paula" changedate="20230519T190127Z" creationid="paula" creationdate="20230519T190127Z">
        <seg>Además, Van Gogh tenía mucho en común con Lautrec: ambos estaban profundamente conmovidos por el arte japonés, con sus líneas finas y curvas y sus figuras complejas.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Besides, shocking stressful situations (both prolonged and short) may also cause depressions, especially if they occur at a tender age (childhood or teenage).</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="paula" changedate="20230521T140450Z" creationid="paula" creationdate="20230521T140450Z">
        <seg>Además, las situaciones estresantes impactantes (tanto prolongadas como breves) también pueden causar depresiones, sobre todo si se producen a una edad temprana (infancia o adolescencia).</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Causes of Depression</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="paula" changedate="20230521T135216Z" creationid="paula" creationdate="20230521T135216Z">
        <seg>Causas de la depresión</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Cezanne and Van Gogh worked together for two years.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="paula" changedate="20230519T184734Z" creationid="paula" creationdate="20230519T184734Z">
        <seg>Cézanne y Van Gogh trabajaron juntos durante dos años.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Cezanne’s impact is visible in Van Gogh’s still lives and fruit paintings, the two painters share similar vague impressionistic oils with hesitant edges and flickering colors.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="paula" changedate="20230519T190703Z" creationid="paula" creationdate="20230519T185958Z">
        <seg>El impacto de Cézanne es visible en los bodegones y los cuadros de frutas de Van Gogh, los dos pintores comparten óleos impresionistas vagos similares con bordes vacilantes y colores parpadeantes.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Cezanne’s work initially was disliked by the public and a lot of fellow painters because he was influenced by Pissarro’s Impressionist style.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="paula" changedate="20230519T183638Z" creationid="paula" creationdate="20230519T183638Z">
        <seg>Al principio, la obra de Cézanne no gustó al público ni a muchos de sus colegas pintores porque estaba influenciada por el estilo impresionista de Pissarro.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Consequently, one of Van Gogh’s pieces exhibits vibrancy and color, which indicate moments of hyperactivity and joy.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="maria" changedate="20230522T115302Z" creationid="maria" creationdate="20230522T115302Z">
        <seg>Así, una de las obras de Van Gogh es vibrante y colorista, lo que indica momentos de hiperactividad y alegría..</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Courbet was a leading reformer being appreciated by other fellow workers.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="paula" changedate="20230521T133106Z" creationid="paula" creationdate="20230521T133106Z">
        <seg>Courbet fue un destacado reformista apreciado por otros compañeros.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Courbet was a painter by birth and drew from quite an early age, using his sisters as subjects.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="paula" changedate="20230521T133004Z" creationid="paula" creationdate="20230521T133004Z">
        <seg>Courbet era pintor de nacimiento y dibujaba desde muy pequeño, utilizando a sus hermanas como sujetos.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Depression</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="paula" changedate="20230521T133133Z" creationid="paula" creationdate="20230521T133133Z">
        <seg>Depresión</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Depression, just like all other psychological and mental disorders is recognized as a clinical issue when it starts to make a serious negative impact on the everyday life of an affected individual (National Institute of Health, 2013).</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="paula" changedate="20230521T135155Z" creationid="paula" creationdate="20230521T135155Z">
        <seg>La depresión, al igual que el resto de trastornos psicológicos y mentales, se reconoce como un problema clínico cuando empieza a tener un grave impacto negativo en la vida cotidiana de un individuo afectado (Institutos Nacionales de Salud, 2013).</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Dr. Felix Rey and Dr. Peyron supported this diagnosis.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="paula" changedate="20230521T165400Z" creationid="paula" creationdate="20230521T165400Z">
        <seg>El Dr. Félix Rey y el Dr. Peyron apoyaron este diagnóstico.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Dr. Gachet, one of Van Gogh’s physicians, treated his illnesses using digitalis that is known to make people see yellow spots.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="paula" changedate="20230521T165522Z" creationid="paula" creationdate="20230521T165522Z">
        <seg>El Dr. Gachet, uno de los médicos de Van Gogh, trataba sus enfermedades con digitalina, conocida por hacer que la gente vea manchas amarillas.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>During his childhood, he was</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="dinag" changedate="20230522T212602Z" creationid="dinag" creationdate="20230522T212602Z">
        <seg>Durante su infancia, fue</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>During his time in Paris in 1886, Van Gogh happened to meet many outstanding artists such as Cormon, Cezanne, Pissarro, Monet, and Gauguin, from whom he learned various art techniques making slight changes in his style and adapting to the world of the Impressionists (Naifeh &amp; Smith, 2011).</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="paula" changedate="20230519T183356Z" creationid="paula" creationdate="20230519T183356Z">
        <seg>Durante su estancia en París en 1886, Van Gogh conoció a muchos artistas destacados como Cormon, Cezanne, Pissarro, Monet y Gauguin, de los que aprendió diversas técnicas artísticas realizando ligeros cambios en su estilo y adaptándose al mundo de los impresionistas (Naifeh &amp; Smith, 2011).</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>During the time between 1860 and 1880 when Van Gogh finally decided to become an artist, he had already seen much in life.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="dinag" changedate="20230522T211202Z" creationid="dinag" creationdate="20230522T210738Z">
        <seg>Durante el tiempo que transcurrió entre 1860 y 1880, cuando Van Gogh decidió finalmente convertirse en artista, ya había visto muchas cosas en la vida.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>During this time they both visited the work of Jean Courbet, a leading painter of that time, and viewed it seriously.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="paula" changedate="20230521T132815Z" creationid="paula" creationdate="20230521T132815Z">
        <seg>Durante este tiempo, ambos visitaron la obra de Jean Courbet, pintor destacado de la época, y la contemplaron con seriedad.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Economic instability led to the growth of the gap between the rich and the poor in Europe.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="paula" changedate="20230507T194722Z" creationid="paula" creationdate="20230507T192628Z">
        <seg>La inestabilidad económica condujo al crecimiento de la brecha entre riqueza y pobreza en Europa.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Edouard Manet (1832-1883) and Henri Matisse (1869- 1954)</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="paula" changedate="20230519T190530Z" creationid="paula" creationdate="20230519T190530Z">
        <seg>Édouard Manet (1832-1883) y Henri Matisse (1869- 1954)</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Edouard Manet’s work showed a connection between realism and post-impressionism.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="paula" changedate="20230519T191037Z" creationid="paula" creationdate="20230519T191037Z">
        <seg>La obra de Édouard Manet muestra una conexión entre el realismo y el postimpresionismo.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Epilepsy was a common disease during Vincent Van Gogh’s lifetime.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="paula" changedate="20230521T165316Z" creationid="paula" creationdate="20230521T165316Z">
        <seg>La epilepsia era una enfermedad común en vida de Vincent Van Gogh.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Even though he was somber, his paintings reflected hope and happiness (Naifeh &amp; Smith, 2011).</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="dinag" changedate="20230522T212137Z" creationid="dinag" creationdate="20230522T212137Z">
        <seg>Aunque era sombrío, sus cuadros reflejaban esperanza y felicidad (Naifeh &amp; Smith, 2011).</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Even though the themes of his work were sometimes somber, Vincent Van Gogh’s paintings reflected hope and happiness.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="dinag" changedate="20230511T200758Z" creationid="dinag" creationdate="20230511T200758Z">
        <seg>Aunque los temas de su obra fueran a veces sombrías, las pinturas de Vincent Van Gogh reflejaban esperanza y felicidad.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Even when it was ridiculed, it rendered a new definition of painting and gave him an iconic status much later (Naifeh &amp; Smith, 2011).</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="dinag" changedate="20230522T212230Z" creationid="dinag" creationdate="20230522T212230Z">
        <seg>Incluso cuando fue ridiculizado, dio una nueva definición de la pintura y le otorgó un estatus icónico mucho tiempo después (Naifeh &amp; Smith, 2011).</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Figure 1 is a photograph of Vincent Van Gogh as a child Vincent Van Gogh was born in Groot-Zundert, the Netherlands, on March 30, 1853.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="dinag" changedate="20230511T204117Z" creationid="dinag" creationdate="20230511T201452Z">
        <seg>La figura 1 es una fotografía de Vincent Van Gogh cuando era pequeño, Vincent Van Gogh nació en Groot-Zundert, Países Bajos, el 30 de marzo de 1853.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Figure 4 is a photograph of Paul Gauguin Vincent Van Gogh was highly influenced by Gauguin.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="dinag" changedate="20230523T093606Z" creationid="dinag" creationdate="20230523T093606Z">
        <seg>La figura 4 es una fotografía de Paul Gauguin Vincent Van Gogh estuvo muy influido por Gauguin. </seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Figure 5 is a timeline showing the important events during Vincent Van Gogh’s life along with important events that were happening in the world at the same time</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="paula" changedate="20230521T160452Z" creationid="paula" creationdate="20230521T160452Z">
        <seg>La figura 5 es una línea de tiempo que muestra los acontecimientos importantes durante la vida de Vincent Van Gogh junto con los acontecimientos importantes que estaban ocurriendo en el mundo al mismo tiempo.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>First of all, in the times of economic instability the families start to push their children into careers they deem the best, the safest, and the most profitable.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="paula" changedate="20230519T182647Z" creationid="paula" creationdate="20230519T182647Z">
        <seg>En primer lugar, en los tiempos de inestabilidad económica, las familias empiezan a empujar a sus hijos a realizar carreras que ellos consideran las mejores, las más seguras y las más provechosas.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Firstly, a person is required to draw a house.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="maria" changedate="20230522T121503Z" creationid="maria" creationdate="20230522T121503Z">
        <seg>En primer lugar, la persona debe dibujar una casa.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>For instance, depressions may appear because of sudden changes in one’s living conditions or habitual environments.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="paula" changedate="20230521T140353Z" creationid="paula" creationdate="20230521T140353Z">
        <seg>Por ejemplo, las depresiones pueden aparecer por cambios bruscos en las condiciones de vida o en el entorno habitual.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>For instance, the well-known incident where Van Gogh used a razor to mutilate his ear in December 1888 can be considered as an act of self-harm caused by emotional overwhelming.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="dinag" changedate="20230523T100340Z" creationid="dinag" creationdate="20230523T100340Z">
        <seg>Por ejemplo, el conocido incidente en el que Van Gogh utilizó una navaja para mutilarse la oreja en diciembre de 1888 puede considerarse un acto de autolesión causado por el agobio emocional. </seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Franco-Prussian War (1870-1871)</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="OmegaT Aligner" changedate="20230507T173348Z" creationid="OmegaT Aligner" creationdate="20230507T173348Z">
        <seg>Guerra franco-prusiana (1870-1871)</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>French Revolution</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="paula" changedate="20230507T195937Z" creationid="paula" creationdate="20230507T195937Z">
        <seg>Revolución Francesa</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Gauguin and Van Gogh were trying to create an artist union in Arles, but their views differed so much that it leads to a conflict.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="maria" changedate="20230511T154845Z" creationid="maria" creationdate="20230511T154845Z">
        <seg>Gauguin y Van Gogh trataron de crear una unión artística en Arlés, pero sus puntos de vista diferían tanto que causó un conflicto.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Gauguin loved Vincent Van Gogh’s sunflower painting and Gauguin bartered for this with his best work &lt;e0&gt;By the Shore of the Lake&lt;/e0&gt;, painted in Martinique which vouched for his adoration for the work (Jansen &amp; Van Gogh, 2007).</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="dinag" changedate="20230523T095945Z" creationid="dinag" creationdate="20230523T095857Z">
        <seg>
A Gauguin le encantaba el cuadro del girasol de Vincent Van Gogh y Gauguin lo canjeó por su mejor obra A la orilla del lago,&lt;/e0&gt; pintada en Martinica, que daba fe de su adoración por la obra (Jansen &amp; Van Gogh, 2007)..</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Gauguin was struck by one painting in an exhibition, Van Gogh’s &lt;e0&gt;Two Sunflowers,&lt;/e0&gt; which is a beautiful blend of colors and techniques and an example of Impressionist painting.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="dinag" changedate="20230523T095107Z" creationid="dinag" creationdate="20230523T093932Z">
        <seg>Gauguin quedó impresionado por un cuadro de una exposición, &lt;e0&gt; Dos girasoles de Van Gogh,&lt;/e0&gt; que es una hermosa mezcla de colores y técnicas y un ejemplo de la pintura impresionista.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Gauguin was very dominating and planned to leave Van Gogh.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="dinag" changedate="20230523T100254Z" creationid="dinag" creationdate="20230523T100254Z">
        <seg>Gauguin era muy dominante y planeaba abandonar a Van Gogh.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Growing up in the conditions of ongoing political conflicts Van Gogh was under constant pressure.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="paula" changedate="20230507T192018Z" creationid="paula" creationdate="20230507T192018Z">
        <seg>Debido a que creció bajo las condiciones de los conflictos políticos en desarrollo, Van Gogh se encontraba bajo una presión constante.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>He also painted things he loved both for their natural beauty and their symbolic significance (Naifeh &amp; Smith, 2011).</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="dinag" changedate="20230523T095903Z" creationid="dinag" creationdate="20230523T095814Z">
        <seg>También pintó cosas que le gustaban tanto por su belleza natural como por su significado simbólico (Naifeh &amp; Smith, 2011).
</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>He and Van Gogh used the same technique of painting.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="paula" changedate="20230521T131445Z" creationid="paula" creationdate="20230521T131445Z">
        <seg>Él y Van Gogh utilizaban la misma técnica de pintura.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>He created 737 canvases, 275 watercolors, 363 prints and posters, 5,084 drawings some ceramic and stained glass work in 20 years.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="paula" changedate="20230519T184434Z" creationid="paula" creationdate="20230519T184434Z">
        <seg>En 20 años creó 737 lienzos, 275 acuarelas, 363 grabados y carteles, 5084 dibujos y algunos trabajos en cerámica y vidrieras.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>He did many paintings in St Remy such as &lt;e0&gt;Olive Trees&lt;/e0&gt; against a slope of the hill, corner in the garden of the hospital, &lt;e1&gt;Starry Night&lt;/e1&gt;, &lt;e2&gt;Old Man in Sorrow&lt;/e2&gt;, and &lt;e3&gt;Road with Cypress and Star&lt;/e3&gt;.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="dinag" changedate="20230523T100823Z" creationid="dinag" creationdate="20230523T100823Z">
        <seg>En St. Remy pintó muchos cuadros,&lt;e0&gt; como Olivos &lt;/e0&gt;  contra la ladera de la colina,Rincón en el jardín del hospital,&lt;e1&gt;Noche estrellada,&lt;/e1&gt;, &lt;e2&gt;Viejo apenado &lt;/e2&gt;, y &lt;e3&gt;Carretera con ciprés y estrella.&lt;/e3&gt;.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>He did not attain notoriety until after his death and thus remained poor throughout his life.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="dinag" changedate="20230511T201932Z" creationid="dinag" creationdate="20230511T201843Z">
        <seg>No alcanzó fama hasta después de su muerte y, por lo tanto, permaneció pobre durante toda su vida..</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>He drew early as a child and ended up as a famous artist, after struggles with mental illness, which may have caused his death (Naifeh &amp; Smith, 2011).</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="dinag" changedate="20230511T203227Z" creationid="dinag" creationdate="20230511T203013Z">
        <seg>Él comenzó a dibujar pronto cuando era muy pequeño, y acabó siendo un artista famoso, después de combatir las enfermedades mentales, que probablemente causaron su muerte.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>He flourished in his art and did a wide range of paintings, whereas the later periods were sad, depressing, and exhausting for him.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="paula" changedate="20230521T165037Z" creationid="paula" creationdate="20230521T165037Z">
        <seg>Floreció en su arte e hizo una gran variedad de cuadros, mientras que los últimos periodos fueron tristes, deprimentes y agotadores para él.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>He left the asylum in 1890 and moved to Auvers-Sur-Oise to continue his treatment.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="dinag" changedate="20230523T100858Z" creationid="dinag" creationdate="20230523T100858Z">
        <seg>Abandona el manicomio en 1890 y se traslada a Auvers-Sur-Oise para continuar su tratamiento. </seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>He painted landscapes, still lives, and sea scopes and social issues.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="paula" changedate="20230521T133024Z" creationid="paula" creationdate="20230521T133024Z">
        <seg>Pintó paisajes, bodegones, marinas y temas sociales.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>He suffered from hallucinations for many months although he had some clear times which he used to draw and work (Greenberg &amp; Jordan, 2001)</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="dinag" changedate="20230523T101025Z" creationid="dinag" creationdate="20230523T101025Z">
        <seg>Sufrió alucinaciones durante muchos meses aunque tuvo algunos momentos de claridad que aprovechó para dibujar y trabajar (Greenberg &amp; Jordan, 2001)</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>He tried working as an art salesman, and even as a preacher in Belgium in 1869; there he was not given much regard because of his bizarre behavior (Stein, 1986) which included episodes of depression and acting out behaviors.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="dinag" changedate="20230522T211243Z" creationid="dinag" creationdate="20230522T211243Z">
        <seg>Intentó trabajar como vendedor de obras de arte e incluso como predicador en Bélgica en 1869; allí no se le tenía mucho aprecio debido a su extraño comportamiento (Stein, 1986), que incluía episodios de depresión y conductas extravagantes.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>He was a very famous draftsman who liked to work on cardboard.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="paula" changedate="20230519T184136Z" creationid="paula" creationdate="20230519T184136Z">
        <seg>Era un dibujante muy famoso al que le gustaba trabajar sobre cartón.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>He was inspired by dark colors and was in close acquaintance with Claude Monet who had similar reflection.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="paula" changedate="20230521T132546Z" creationid="paula" creationdate="20230521T132546Z">
        <seg>Le inspiraban los colores oscuros y mantenía una estrecha relación con Claude Monet, que tenía una reflexión similar.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>He worked with thick layers of pastel and simple shapes (Van Gogh &amp; Powell, 2003).</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="paula" changedate="20230519T183838Z" creationid="paula" creationdate="20230519T183838Z">
        <seg>Trabajaba con gruesas capas de pastel y formas sencillas (Van Gogh &amp; Powell, 2003).</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Henri De Toulouse Lautrec (1864- 1901)</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="paula" changedate="20230521T132918Z" creationid="paula" creationdate="20230521T132918Z">
        <seg>Henri d Toulouse Lautrec (1864- 1901)</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Henri Matisse was born in a middle-class family and wanted to study law.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="paula" changedate="20230521T131259Z" creationid="paula" creationdate="20230521T131259Z">
        <seg>Henri Matisse nació en una familia de clase media y quería estudiar Derecho.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>His artwork undoubtedly served as some therapy to him.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="OmegaT Aligner" changedate="20230512T004200Z" creationid="OmegaT Aligner" creationdate="20230512T004200Z">
        <seg>Sin duda, su obra de arte le sirvió de terapia.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>His doctors believed this, as well as his epileptic condition, was caused by his alcohol abuse.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="paula" changedate="20230521T165448Z" creationid="paula" creationdate="20230521T165448Z">
        <seg>Sus médicos creían que esto, así como su estado epiléptico, estaba causado por su abuso del alcohol.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>His emotional troubles were often reflected in his art pieces.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="maria" changedate="20230522T115152Z" creationid="maria" creationdate="20230522T115152Z">
        <seg>Sus problemas emocionales se reflejaban a menudo en sus obras de arte.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>His experiences included two failed romantic relationships and stints at odd jobs like that were mostly unsuccessful such as becoming a clerk in a bookstore.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="dinag" changedate="20230522T211212Z" creationid="dinag" creationdate="20230522T211212Z">
        <seg>Sus experiencias incluyeron dos relaciones románticas fallidas y trabajos esporádicos que en su mayoría fueron infructuosos, como el de dependiente en una librería.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>His impressionist forms were influenced by his close collaborations with artists such as Mantic, Gauguin, Lautrec, and Cezanne.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="OmegaT Aligner" changedate="20230512T004200Z" creationid="OmegaT Aligner" creationdate="20230512T004200Z">
        <seg>Sus formas impresionistas se vieron influidas por sus estrechas colaboraciones con artistas como Mantic, Gauguin, Lautrec y Cezanne.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>His manic personality is thought to be the source of his extreme enthusiasm for religion and art.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="dinag" changedate="20230522T211539Z" creationid="dinag" creationdate="20230522T211539Z">
        <seg>Se cree que su personalidad maníaca era el origen de su extremo entusiasmo por la religión y el arte.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>His massive collection of over 800 letters was attributed to a condition called Hypergraphia, a disorder linked to mania and epilepsy, where a person needlessly writes continuously (Naifeh &amp; Smith, 2011).</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="dinag" changedate="20230522T211736Z" creationid="dinag" creationdate="20230522T211736Z">
        <seg>Su enorme colección de más de 800 cartas se atribuyó a una afección llamada hipergrafía, un trastorno vinculado a la manía y la epilepsia, en el que una persona escribe sin necesidad continuamente (Naifeh &amp; Smith, 2011).
</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>His works are subtle and filled with light.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="dinag" changedate="20230522T211924Z" creationid="dinag" creationdate="20230522T211924Z">
        <seg>Sus obras son sutiles y llenas de luz.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Historical Background</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="paula" changedate="20230507T195902Z" creationid="paula" creationdate="20230507T195902Z">
        <seg>Trasfondo Histórico</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>House in this test is a symbolic interpretation of a person’s relationships with his or her surroundings (Knoff, 2003).</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="maria" changedate="20230522T180334Z" creationid="maria" creationdate="20230522T180334Z">
        <seg>La casa en este test es una interpretación simbólica de las relaciones de una persona con su entorno (Knoff, 2003).</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>However the brief friendship between these artists dissolved fast and Lautrec didn’t hear from Van Gogh after that (Van Gogh &amp; Powell, 2003).</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="paula" changedate="20230519T190439Z" creationid="paula" creationdate="20230519T190439Z">
        <seg>Sin embargo, la breve amistad entre estos artistas se disolvió rápidamente y Lautrec no volvió a saber nada de Van Gogh (Van Gogh &amp; Powell, 2003).</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>However, after a short period, the individual suddenly becomes downcast and unhappy.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="maria" changedate="20230522T120332Z" creationid="maria" creationdate="20230522T120332Z">
        <seg>Sin embargo, tras un breve periodo, el individuo se vuelve reentinamente abatido e infeliz.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>However, it is believed that he suffered from several mental illnesses (Naifeh &amp; Smith, 2011).</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="dinag" changedate="20230511T204158Z" creationid="dinag" creationdate="20230511T201822Z">
        <seg>Sin embargo, se cree que él sufría de enfermedades mentales graves.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Huysmans helped Vincent Van Gogh understand the nuances of painting and helped him grasp the concepts by having a concise and structured perception towards art.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="dinag" changedate="20230522T212740Z" creationid="dinag" creationdate="20230522T212740Z">
        <seg>Huysmans ayudó a Vincent Van Gogh a entender los matices de la pintura y le ayudó a captar los conceptos teniendo una percepción concisa y estructurada hacia el arte. </seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Hypergraphia</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="HP" changedate="20230511T160956Z" creationid="HP" creationdate="20230511T160956Z">
        <seg>Hipergrafía</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>I want you to draw me as good a picture of a house as you can.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="maria" changedate="20230522T121718Z" creationid="maria" creationdate="20230522T121718Z">
        <seg>Quiero que me haga el mejor dibujo posible de una casa.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>In 1861, eleven states in the United States wanted to secede from the union of states and form their own confederate American country.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="OmegaT Aligner" changedate="20230507T173348Z" creationid="OmegaT Aligner" creationdate="20230507T173348Z">
        <seg>En 1861, once estados de Estados Unidos querían separarse de la unión de estados y formar su propio país confederado americano.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>In 1886 Vincent moved to Paris where he lived with Theo who was the manager of Goupil’s gallery.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="dinag" changedate="20230523T093130Z" creationid="dinag" creationdate="20230523T093130Z">
        <seg>En 1886 Vincent se trasladó a París, donde vivió con Theo, que era el director de la galería de Goupil.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>In February 1889, the residents of Arles complained to the authorities that Van Gogh should be placed in an asylum on account of his mental conditions and the depression he was suffering.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="paula" changedate="20230521T161139Z" creationid="paula" creationdate="20230521T161139Z">
        <seg>En febrero de 1889, los habitantes de Arles se quejan a las autoridades de que Van Gogh debe ser internado en un manicomio debido a su estado mental y a la depresión que sufre.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>In October of 1888, Gauguin and Van Gogh agreed to work together and decorate the yellow house when they arrived in Arles.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="paula" changedate="20230521T132739Z" creationid="paula" creationdate="20230521T132739Z">
        <seg>En octubre de 1888, Gauguin y Van Gogh acuerdan trabajar juntos y decorar la casa amarilla cuando lleguen a Arles.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>In describing the mutual friendship and artistic relationship between Vincent and Gauguin, it will be noted that Gauguin greatly admired Gogh’s paintings.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="OmegaT Aligner" changedate="20230511T161419Z" creationid="OmegaT Aligner" creationdate="20230511T161419Z">
        <seg>Al describir la amistad mutua y la relación artística entre Vincent y Gauguin, se observará que Gauguin admiraba mucho los cuadros de Gogh.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>In the book, it is explained how Theo was so close to Vincent Van Gogh that Theo himself died soon after Vincent.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="dinag" changedate="20230523T093358Z" creationid="dinag" creationdate="20230523T093257Z">
        <seg>En el libro, se explica cómo Theo estaba tan unido a Vincent Van Gogh que el propio Theo murió poco después que Vincent.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>In these letters to his brother, Vincent disclosed the pain and inner conflicts that affected him throughout his life.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="dinag" changedate="20230523T093339Z" creationid="dinag" creationdate="20230523T093339Z">
        <seg>En estas cartas a su hermano, Vincent reveló el dolor y los conflictos interiores que le afectaron a lo largo de su vida. </seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>In this house, Vincent had finally found some good friends and was not only painting but communicating as well (Gayford, 2008).</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="maria" changedate="20230522T180942Z" creationid="maria" creationdate="20230522T180942Z">
        <seg>En esta casa, Vincent había encontrado por fin buenos amigos y no sólo pintaba, sino que también se comunicaba (Gayford, 2008).</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>In this section of the paper, I would like to analyze Van Gogh’s personality using his The Yellow House and the house-tree-person test since exactly these objects are painted in the picture.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="maria" changedate="20230522T120752Z" creationid="maria" creationdate="20230522T120752Z">
        <seg>En esta sección del artículo, me gustaría analizar la personalidad de Van Gogh a partir de "La casa amarilla" y el test de la casa-árbol-persona, ya que en el cuadro aparecen exactamente estos objetos.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Influence of other artists</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="paula" changedate="20230519T183218Z" creationid="paula" creationdate="20230519T183218Z">
        <seg>Influencia de otros artistas</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Influence of the Political Scenario on Van Gogh</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="paula" changedate="20230507T191830Z" creationid="paula" creationdate="20230507T191830Z">
        <seg>La influencia del escenario político en Van Gogh</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Introduction</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="dinag" changedate="20230511T204111Z" creationid="dinag" creationdate="20230511T201120Z">
        <seg>Introducción.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>It can be concluded that the events of Van Gogh’s childhood predisposed him to his disease, and the later failures worsened his condition.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="OmegaT Aligner" changedate="20230512T004200Z" creationid="OmegaT Aligner" creationdate="20230512T004200Z">
        <seg>Se puede concluir que los acontecimientos de la infancia de Van Gogh le predispusieron a su enfermedad, y los fracasos posteriores empeoraron su estado.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>It can tell about both the relations with an individual’s family and close friends.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="maria" changedate="20230522T180405Z" creationid="maria" creationdate="20230522T180405Z">
        <seg>Puede informar tanto sobre las relaciones con la familia como con los amigos íntimos de un individuo.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>It is believed that his mental anxiety and extreme seclusion from the world might account for his demise (Gayford, 2006).</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="dinag" changedate="20230523T101227Z" creationid="dinag" creationdate="20230523T101227Z">
        <seg>Se cree que su ansiedad mental y su extrema reclusión del mundo podrían explicar su fallecimiento (Gayford, 2006).
</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>It is believed to be important to describe the background of what was happening in the world, and in the artistic community, especially in France, during the period when Van Gogh was alive and living and working in France and other parts of Europe.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="paula" changedate="20230507T195914Z" creationid="paula" creationdate="20230507T195914Z">
        <seg>Se cree que es importante describir el trasfondo de lo que estaba sucediendo e el mundo, y en la comunidad artística, especialmente en Francia, durante el periodo en el que Van Gogh estaba vivo y vivía y trabajaba en Francia y otras partes de Europa.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>It is possible that the stress of this relationship caused an increase in Vincent’s mental disorders.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="OmegaT Aligner" changedate="20230511T161419Z" creationid="OmegaT Aligner" creationdate="20230511T161419Z">
        <seg>Es posible que el estrés de esta relación provocara un aumento de los trastornos mentales de Vincent.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>It is still unknown what role the illness played in his success as a painter.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="OmegaT Aligner" changedate="20230512T004200Z" creationid="OmegaT Aligner" creationdate="20230512T004200Z">
        <seg>Aún se desconoce qué papel desempeñó la enfermedad en su éxito como pintor.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>It is visible hos strongly the artist was influenced by his outstanding contemporaries.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="dinag" changedate="20230523T095236Z" creationid="dinag" creationdate="20230523T095236Z">
        <seg>Es evidente que el artista estaba muy influido por sus contemporáneos más destacados.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>It was clear that since his childhood, Vincent Van Gogh had an early inclination towards painting and he eventually created 2100 artworks comprised of oil paintings, watercolors, art, sketches, and self-portraits which vouch for his talent.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="dinag" changedate="20230522T212820Z" creationid="dinag" creationdate="20230522T212820Z">
        <seg>Estaba claro que desde su infancia, Vincent Van Gogh tuvo una inclinación temprana hacia la pintura y finalmente creó 2100 obras de arte compuestas por óleos, acuarelas, arte, bocetos y autorretratos que dan fe de su talento.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>It was in Paris where Van Gogh met many other French painters like Henri Matisse and Edouard Manet.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="paula" changedate="20230519T190614Z" creationid="paula" creationdate="20230519T190614Z">
        <seg>Fue en París donde Van Gogh conoció a muchos otros pintores franceses como Henri Matisse y Édouard Manet.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>It was on the unfortunate day of 27 July 1890 that Van Gogh committed suicide by shooting himself in his chest; he died the following day after his wound became infected.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="dinag" changedate="20230523T101147Z" creationid="dinag" creationdate="20230523T101147Z">
        <seg>El 27 de julio de 1890, Van Gogh se suicidó de un disparo en el pecho y murió al día siguiente, tras infectarse la herida.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>It was the time between the 1860s and 1880s that he was most productive, and finally decided to become an artist after he had seen and experienced much in life.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="OmegaT Aligner" changedate="20230511T161419Z" creationid="OmegaT Aligner" creationdate="20230511T161419Z">
        <seg>Fue la época entre 1860 y 1880 cuando fue más productivo, y finalmente decidió convertirse en artista después de haber visto y experimentado mucho en la vida.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Just draw me as good a house as you can.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="maria" changedate="20230522T122215Z" creationid="maria" creationdate="20230522T122215Z">
        <seg>Simplemente dibújame una casa tan buena como puedas.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Later in 1889, Van Gogh committed himself to a mental asylum in St. Remy and ended his friendship with Gauguin.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="dinag" changedate="20230523T100505Z" creationid="dinag" creationdate="20230523T100505Z">
        <seg>Más tarde, en 1889, Van Gogh se internó en un manicomio de St. Remy y puso fin a su amistad con Gauguin.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Later in May of the same year, Van Gogh turned himself into the asylum at Remy and was allowed to paint.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="paula" changedate="20230521T164757Z" creationid="paula" creationdate="20230521T164757Z">
        <seg>En mayo de ese mismo año, Van Gogh ingresa en el manicomio de Remy y se le permite pintar.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Later, he dedicated most of his time to smoking and drinking which finally lead to extreme depression and his suicide.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="paula" changedate="20230521T165143Z" creationid="paula" creationdate="20230521T165143Z">
        <seg>Más tarde, dedicó la mayor parte de su tiempo a fumar y beber, lo que finalmente le condujo a una depresión extrema y a su suicidio.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Later, there was some competition and friction between them.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="dinag" changedate="20230511T211419Z" creationid="dinag" creationdate="20230511T211419Z">
        <seg>Más tarde, hubo cierta competencia y fricción entre ellos.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Later, they became close to each other for they could relate their shared desire to give a new form to their imaginations as artists struggling to earn a name in the highly confounding impressionist art form.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="dinag" changedate="20230511T162351Z" creationid="OmegaT Aligner" creationdate="20230511T161419Z">
        <seg>Más tarde, se hicieron íntimos el uno del otro porque podían relacionar su deseo compartido de dar una nueva forma a sus imaginaciones como artistas que luchaban por ganarse un nombre en la más confusa forma de arte impresionista.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Lautrec and Van Gogh later met again at Julien Pere Tanguy’s paint store to view Paul Cezanne’s painting.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="paula" changedate="20230519T184704Z" creationid="paula" creationdate="20230519T184704Z">
        <seg>Más tarde, Lautrec y Van Gogh vuelven a encontrarse en la tienda de pinturas de Julien Pere Tanguy para ver el cuadro de Paul Cézanne.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Lautrec was born in 1864 at Albi.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="paula" changedate="20230519T184107Z" creationid="paula" creationdate="20230519T184107Z">
        <seg>Lautrec nació en 1864 en Albi.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Life of Vincent Van Gogh (1853-1889)</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="dinag" changedate="20230511T211739Z" creationid="dinag" creationdate="20230511T211739Z">
        <seg>La vida de Vincent Van Gogh (1853-1889)</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Likewise, it is unknown what the illness was: the most popular versions are depression and bipolar disorder.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="maria" changedate="20230511T154529Z" creationid="maria" creationdate="20230511T154529Z">
        <seg>Asimismo, se desconoce qué era la enfermedad: las versiones más populares eran depresión y transtorno bipolar.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Literature Review</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="dinag" changedate="20230511T211720Z" creationid="dinag" creationdate="20230511T211720Z">
        <seg>Revisión bibliográfica</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Manet died early in 1883.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="paula" changedate="20230521T130932Z" creationid="paula" creationdate="20230521T130932Z">
        <seg>Manet murió a principios de 1883.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Many physicians even argue that Thujone also causes one to see things in yellow (Tralbaut, 1969).</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="paula" changedate="20230521T170349Z" creationid="paula" creationdate="20230521T170349Z">
        <seg>Muchos médicos incluso sostienen que la tuyona también hace que uno vea las cosas de color amarillo (Tralbaut, 1969).</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Matisse was interested in post-impressionism and studied the works of Van Gogh and Paul Cezanne (Spurling, 1998).</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="paula" changedate="20230521T132102Z" creationid="paula" creationdate="20230521T132102Z">
        <seg>Matisse se interesó por el postimpresionismo y estudió las obras de Van Gogh y Paul Cézanne (Spurling, 1998).</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Mental Illness</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="maria" changedate="20230511T154540Z" creationid="maria" creationdate="20230511T154540Z">
        <seg>Enfermedad Mental</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Methodology</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="HP" changedate="20230513T144453Z" creationid="HP" creationdate="20230513T144308Z">
        <seg>Metodología</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Moreover, Van Gogh and his friend Gauguin wanted to</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="maria" changedate="20230522T181800Z" creationid="maria" creationdate="20230522T181800Z">
        <seg>Además, Van Gogh y su amigo Gauguin querían</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Moreover, it is recognized as the cause of his incredibly fast art production.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="dinag" changedate="20230522T211647Z" creationid="dinag" creationdate="20230522T211647Z">
        <seg>Además, se le reconoce como la causa de su producción artística increíblemente rápida.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Naifeh and Smith (2011) reveal the changes in the life of Van Gogh after he started to develop his impressionist style and re-invent the dimensions of art Vincent Van Gogh’s paintings and his talent made him immortal.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="dinag" changedate="20230522T212114Z" creationid="dinag" creationdate="20230522T212114Z">
        <seg>Naifeh y Smith (2011) revelan los cambios en la vida de Van Gogh después de que comenzó a desarrollar su estilo impresionista y a reinventar las dimensiones del arte Las pinturas de Vincent Van Gogh y su talento lo hicieron inmortal.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Nevertheless, Paul Cezanne is considered one of the greatest revolutionary artists of the late 19&lt;s0&gt;th&lt;/s0&gt; and early 20&lt;s1&gt;th&lt;/s1&gt; centuries.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="paula" changedate="20230519T183800Z" creationid="paula" creationdate="20230519T183800Z">
        <seg>Sin embargo, Paul Cézanne está considerado uno de los mayores artistas revolucionarios de finales del siglo XIX y principios del XX.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>No foreign countries came to help the eleven states of the confederacy.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="OmegaT Aligner" changedate="20230507T173348Z" creationid="OmegaT Aligner" creationdate="20230507T173348Z">
        <seg>Ningún país extranjero acudió en ayuda de los once estados de la confederación.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Not only his style but the subjects were adapted from the works of the Impressionists – flowers, well-lit sceneries, still lives.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="dinag" changedate="20230523T095625Z" creationid="dinag" creationdate="20230523T095625Z">
        <seg>No sólo su estilo, sino también los temas, fueron adaptados de las obras de los impresionistas: flores, paisajes bien iluminados, bodegones.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>On 23&lt;s0&gt;rd&lt;/s0&gt; December 1888, Van Gogh tried to cut off his ear after running to Gauguin with a razor after Van Gogh had been informed of Gauguin’s decision to leave.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="paula" changedate="20230521T160728Z" creationid="paula" creationdate="20230521T160728Z">
        <seg>El 23 &lt;s0&gt;de&lt;/s0&gt; diciembre de 1888, Van Gogh intentó cortarse la oreja tras correr hacia Gauguin con una navaja de afeitar después de que este le informara de la decisión de Gauguin de marcharse.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>On the contrary, other pieces are dark this was a period of gloom and depression for Van Gogh.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="maria" changedate="20230522T115431Z" creationid="maria" creationdate="20230522T115431Z">
        <seg>Por el contrario, otras obras son oscuras, lo que supone un periodo de tristeza y depresión para Van Gogh.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>One of them was Bipolar disorder formerly referred to as manic depression.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="dinag" changedate="20230522T211438Z" creationid="dinag" creationdate="20230522T211438Z">
        <seg>Uno de ellos era el trastorno bipolar, antes conocido como depresión maníaca.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Other indicators that he might have had bipolar disorder can be seen if we carefully examine Vincent Van Gogh’s life history where it can be easily noted that Vincent Van Gogh’s life was separated into different periods.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="paula" changedate="20230521T164947Z" creationid="paula" creationdate="20230521T164947Z">
        <seg>Otros indicadores de que podría haber padecido un trastorno bipolar pueden verse si examinamos detenidamente la historia vital de Vincent Van Gogh, donde puede observarse fácilmente que la vida de Vincent Van Gogh estuvo separada en distintos periodos.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Other possible causes of mental and physical illness</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="paula" changedate="20230521T165223Z" creationid="paula" creationdate="20230521T165223Z">
        <seg>Otras posibles causas de enfermedades mentales y físicas</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Other traumatizing events are conflicts and losses, lack of stable support from the close ones, other personal problems, alcohol, and substance abuse (Raynor, 2013).</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="paula" changedate="20230521T140858Z" creationid="paula" creationdate="20230521T140858Z">
        <seg>Otros acontecimientos traumatizantes son los conflictos y las pérdidas, la falta de apoyo estable de los allegados, otros problemas personales, el alcohol y el abuso de sustancias (Raynor, 2013).</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Overall, the nature of depression is not understood entirely and it considered multi-factorial.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="paula" changedate="20230521T135422Z" creationid="paula" creationdate="20230521T135422Z">
        <seg>En general, la naturaleza de la depresión no se comprende del todo y se considera multifactorial.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Paul Cezanne (1839-1906)</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="paula" changedate="20230519T183656Z" creationid="paula" creationdate="20230519T183656Z">
        <seg>Paul Cézanne (1839-1906)</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Paul Cezanne met Van Gogh in 1873.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="paula" changedate="20230519T183646Z" creationid="paula" creationdate="20230519T183532Z">
        <seg>Paul Cézanne conoció a Van Gogh en 1873.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Paul Cezanne’s work laid the foundation for Post-Impressionist painting in France.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="paula" changedate="20230519T183650Z" creationid="paula" creationdate="20230519T183503Z">
        <seg>La obra de Paul Cézanne sentó las bases de la pintura postimpresionista en Francia.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Paul Gauguin had been very impressed by Vincent Van Gogh ’s exceptional talent when he first came upon Vincent’s work (Naifeh &amp; Smith, 2011).</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="dinag" changedate="20230523T093644Z" creationid="dinag" creationdate="20230523T093644Z">
        <seg>Paul Gauguin quedó muy impresionado por el excepcional talento de Vincent Van Gogh cuando conoció la obra de Vincent (Naifeh &amp; Smith, 2011).</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Physically, he recovered speedily and was taken home, but still suffered from hallucinations of being poisoned, and had other symptoms of mental illness (Greenberg &amp; Jordan, 2001).</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="dinag" changedate="20230523T100427Z" creationid="dinag" creationdate="20230523T100427Z">
        <seg>Físicamente, se recuperó con rapidez y fue llevado a casa, pero seguía sufriendo alucinaciones de haber sido envenenado y tenía otros síntomas de enfermedad mental (Greenberg &amp; Jordan, 2001).</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Prussia was grasping power in the southern provinces of Germany and France wanted compensation in Belgium to maintain the balance of power in Europe.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="OmegaT Aligner" changedate="20230507T173348Z" creationid="OmegaT Aligner" creationdate="20230507T173348Z">
        <seg>Prusia se hacía con el poder en las provincias del sur de Alemania y Francia quería una compensación en Bélgica para mantener el equilibrio de poder en Europa.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Relationship with Paul Gauguin</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="dinag" changedate="20230523T093545Z" creationid="dinag" creationdate="20230523T093545Z">
        <seg>La relación con Paul Gauguin</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Relationship with his brother</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="dinag" changedate="20230523T092513Z" creationid="dinag" creationdate="20230523T092513Z">
        <seg>La relación con su hermano</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Renoir had a series of best 181 paintings that have been reproduced often (Krell &amp; Manet, 1996).</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="paula" changedate="20230521T132611Z" creationid="paula" creationdate="20230521T132611Z">
        <seg>Renoir tenía una serie de 181 mejores cuadros que se han reproducido a menudo (Krell &amp; Manet, 1996).</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Renoir was a leading painter in post-impressionism and his basic subject of study became the female.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="paula" changedate="20230521T132509Z" creationid="paula" creationdate="20230521T132509Z">
        <seg>Renoir fue uno de los principales pintores del postimpresionismo y su tema básico de estudio fue la mujer.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Some experts state that depression occurs due to the genetic factors, others maintain that it develops because of the external factors (Raynor, 2013).</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="paula" changedate="20230521T135622Z" creationid="paula" creationdate="20230521T135622Z">
        <seg>Algunos expertos afirman que la depresión se produce debido a los factores genéticos, otros sostienen que se desarrolla debido a los factores externos (Raynor, 2013).</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Sommers (2003) explains manic depression as a mental disorder that enables one to experience moments of extreme joy and hyperactivity.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="maria" changedate="20230522T120237Z" creationid="maria" creationdate="20230522T120237Z">
        <seg>Sommers (2003) explica la depresión maníaca como un transtorno mental que permite experimentar momentos de extrema alegría e hiperactividad.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Soon after the American Civil War, France lost an important war to Prussia against Germany.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="OmegaT Aligner" changedate="20230507T173348Z" creationid="OmegaT Aligner" creationdate="20230507T173348Z">
        <seg>Poco después de la Guerra Civil estadounidense, Francia perdió una importante guerra contra Alemania a manos de Prusia.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Soon before the birth of Van Gogh, civil war broke out in Europe, specifically the French Revolution which had an impact on everyone’s lives.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="paula" changedate="20230507T195948Z" creationid="paula" creationdate="20230507T195948Z">
        <seg>Poco antes del nacimiento de Van Gogh, estalló la Guerra Civil en Europa, específicamente la Revolución Francesa, la cual tuvo impacto en las vidas de todo el mundo.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Soon, problems arose between the two due to differences like their personalities (Naifeh &amp; Smith, 2011).</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="dinag" changedate="20230523T100222Z" creationid="dinag" creationdate="20230523T100222Z">
        <seg>Pronto surgieron problemas entre ambos debido a diferencias como sus personalidades (Naifeh y Smith, 2011).</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Such behaviors are common for people with bipolar disorder.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="dinag" changedate="20230523T100414Z" creationid="dinag" creationdate="20230523T100414Z">
        <seg>Tales comportamientos son habituales en personas con trastorno bipolar.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Such examples of depression along with the dynamic stages of over- an enthusiasm he showed frequently as an artist are now considered mostly to have been bipolar disorder (Bush, 2014).</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="paula" changedate="20230521T153633Z" creationid="paula" creationdate="20230521T153633Z">
        <seg>Tales ejemplos de depresión junto con las fases dinámicas de un sobre entusiasmo que mostraba con frecuencia como artista se consideran ahora en su mayoría trastorno bipolar (Bush, 2014).</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Sunstroke</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="HP" changedate="20230511T161012Z" creationid="HP" creationdate="20230511T161012Z">
        <seg>Sol</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Take one of these pencils, please.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="maria" changedate="20230522T121546Z" creationid="maria" creationdate="20230522T121546Z">
        <seg>Coja uno de estos lápices, por favor.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Temporal Lobe Epilepsy</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="paula" changedate="20230521T165301Z" creationid="paula" creationdate="20230521T165301Z">
        <seg>Epilepsia del lóbulo temporal</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>The Civil War began and continued for four years.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="OmegaT Aligner" changedate="20230507T173348Z" creationid="OmegaT Aligner" creationdate="20230507T173348Z">
        <seg>La Guerra Civil comenzó y continuó durante cuatro años.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>The French Revolution is also commonly called the February Revolution and lasted from 23&lt;s0&gt;rd&lt;/s0&gt; February until 2&lt;s1&gt;nd&lt;/s1&gt; December 1848.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="paula" changedate="20230519T181116Z" creationid="paula" creationdate="20230519T181116Z">
        <seg>La Revolución Francesa, también llamada Revolución de Febrero, duró desde el 23 &lt;s0&gt;de&lt;/s0&gt; febrero hasta el 2&lt;s1&gt;de&lt;/s1&gt; diciembre de 1848.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>The French army had a handful of people against a large number of people in Prussia.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="paula" changedate="20230519T185004Z" creationid="paula" creationdate="20230519T185004Z">
        <seg>El ejército francés tenía un puñado de personas contra un gran número de personas en Prusia.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>The United States government did not want them to secede.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="OmegaT Aligner" changedate="20230507T173348Z" creationid="OmegaT Aligner" creationdate="20230507T173348Z">
        <seg>El gobierno de Estados Unidos no quería que se separaran.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>The Yellow House</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="maria" changedate="20230512T005501Z" creationid="OmegaT Aligner" creationdate="20230512T004200Z">
        <seg>La Casa Amarilla</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>The art of Impressionism that affected Van Gogh’s style so much derived from the dire historical environments as an opposition to the depressive reality with the help of non-sentimental themes, bright light, and cheerful colors.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="paula" changedate="20230507T195042Z" creationid="paula" creationdate="20230507T193305Z">
        <seg>El arte del Impresionismo que tanto afectó al estilo de Van Gogh, deriva de los nefastos entornos históricos como oposición a la despresiva realidad con la ayuda de  temas no sentimentales, luz brillante y colores alegres.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>The cause of his death was a self-inflicted gunshot wound.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="dinag" changedate="20230511T203502Z" creationid="dinag" creationdate="20230511T202144Z">
        <seg>La causa de su muerte fue una herida de bala autoinfligida.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>The civil war was an uprising that had grown in the minds of the men of Europe so they could overcome the monarchy and rule their own lives.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="paula" changedate="20230507T200006Z" creationid="paula" creationdate="20230507T200006Z">
        <seg>La Guerra Civil fue un levantamiento que creció en las mentes de los hombres europeos de manera que pudieran vencer a la monarquía y dirigir sus propias vidas.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>The examiner gives the following instructions.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="maria" changedate="20230522T121522Z" creationid="maria" creationdate="20230522T121522Z">
        <seg>El examinador da las siguientes instrucciones.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>The first flare-up of his illness occurred with Paul Gauguin.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="maria" changedate="20230511T154627Z" creationid="maria" creationdate="20230511T154627Z">
        <seg>El primer brote de su enfermedad ocurrió con Paul Gauguin.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>The first period was the one in which he showed great enthusiasm and excitement towards his religion.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="paula" changedate="20230521T165007Z" creationid="paula" creationdate="20230521T165007Z">
        <seg>El primer periodo fue aquel en el que mostró un gran entusiasmo y emoción hacia su religión.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>The greatest achievement of the genius that Vincent Van Gogh was that his art was ahead of its time.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="dinag" changedate="20230522T212204Z" creationid="dinag" creationdate="20230522T212204Z">
        <seg>El mayor logro del genio que fue Vincent Van Gogh fue que su arte se adelantó a su tiempo.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>The house-tree-person test is a personality test with the help of an individual’s drawings and his or her subsequent responses to questions reveal various aspects of the personality.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="maria" changedate="20230522T120903Z" creationid="maria" creationdate="20230522T120903Z">
        <seg>El test de la casa-árbol-persona es un test de personalidad que se realiza con la ayuda de los dibujos de un individuo y sus posteriores respuestas a las preguntas revelan diversos aspectos de su personalidad.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>The influence of the French empire ended and unified Germany was formed which created a balance of power in Europe and the formation of the French Third Republic (Howard, 2001).</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="paula" changedate="20230519T185347Z" creationid="paula" creationdate="20230519T185347Z">
        <seg>La influencia del Imperio francés terminó y se formó la Alemania unificada, lo que creó un equilibrio de poder en Europa y la formación de la tercera República francesa (Howard, 2001).</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>The main cause of this war was the unification of Germany.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="OmegaT Aligner" changedate="20230507T173348Z" creationid="OmegaT Aligner" creationdate="20230507T173348Z">
        <seg>La causa principal de esta guerra fue la unificación de Alemania.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>The next day he went to a mental hospital at Saint-Remy.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="maria" changedate="20230511T155227Z" creationid="maria" creationdate="20230511T155227Z">
        <seg>Al día siguiente fue a un hospital psiquiátrico en Saint-Rémy.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>The problem of the connection between Van Gogh’s artistic talent and his mental illness is still unsolved.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="maria" changedate="20230511T154336Z" creationid="maria" creationdate="20230511T154336Z">
        <seg>El problema de la conexión entre el talento artístico de Van Gogh y su enfermedad mental está aún sin resolver.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>The question of the influence on the work of his relationship with Gauguin and possible mental illness will be investigated and discussed.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="dinag" changedate="20230511T204252Z" creationid="dinag" creationdate="20230511T200558Z">
        <seg>La cuestión de la influencia en su obra con su amistad con Gauguin y la posible enfermedad mental serán investigados y profundizados.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>The research method adopted in this thesis follows a historical framework.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="dinag" changedate="20230511T201103Z" creationid="dinag" creationdate="20230511T201103Z">
        <seg>El método de búsqueda adoptada en esta tesis sigue un marco histórico.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>The rule of Louis-Phillippe was put to an end and thus was born the French Second Republic which was led by Louis Napoleon (Tocqueville, 1986).</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="paula" changedate="20230519T182055Z" creationid="paula" creationdate="20230519T182055Z">
        <seg>El gobierno de Louis-Phillippe llegó a su fin y así nació la Segunda República Francesa, dirigida por Louis Napoleón (Tocqueville, 1986).</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>The scientists still argue whether depressions are inflicted from within or from without.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="paula" changedate="20230521T135310Z" creationid="paula" creationdate="20230521T135310Z">
        <seg>Los científicos siguen discutiendo si las depresiones se infligen desde dentro o desde fuera.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>The story of how their friendship developed is very interesting.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="dinag" changedate="20230523T093817Z" creationid="dinag" creationdate="20230523T093817Z">
        <seg>La historia del desarrollo de su amistad es muy interesante.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>The theory that depressions may run in families comes from the perspective that if a child tends to witness a parent suffering from depression, they become likely to develop a depression of their own over time.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="paula" changedate="20230521T140246Z" creationid="paula" creationdate="20230521T140246Z">
        <seg>La teoría de que las depresiones pueden ser hereditarias parte de la perspectiva de que si un niño tiende a presenciar cómo uno de sus padres sufre una depresión, es probable que con el tiempo desarrolle una depresión propia.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>The three most important world history events were the French Revolution, the American Civil War, and the Franco-Prussian war in Europe.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="paula" changedate="20230507T195924Z" creationid="paula" creationdate="20230507T195924Z">
        <seg>Los tres eventos más importantes de la historia mundial fueron la Revolución Francesa, la Guerra Civil Americana y la Guerra franco-prusiana en Europa.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>The war lasted a long time and had a series of battles.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="paula" changedate="20230519T185028Z" creationid="paula" creationdate="20230519T185028Z">
        <seg>La guerra duró mucho tiempo y tuvo una serie de batallas.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>The work of Jean Courbet was very highly appreciated by Van Gogh and Henri De Toulouse Lautrec.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="paula" changedate="20230521T132911Z" creationid="paula" creationdate="20230521T132911Z">
        <seg>La obra de Jean Courbet fue muy apreciada por Van Gogh y Henri de Toulouse Lautrec.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Their collaboration ended dramatically around Christmas Eve, 1888, followed by a series of violent incidents (Greenberg &amp; Jordan, 2001)</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="dinag" changedate="20230511T211709Z" creationid="dinag" creationdate="20230511T211709Z">
        <seg>Su colaboración terminó de forma dramática alrededor de la Nochebuena de 1888, seguida de una serie de incidentes violentos (Greenberg &amp; Jordan, 2001)</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Them the examiner gives the same instructions for the tree and person drawings.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="maria" changedate="20230522T122435Z" creationid="maria" creationdate="20230522T122435Z">
        <seg>A continuación, el examinador da las mismas instrucciones para los dibujos de árboles y personas.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Then, considering both the character of drawings and an individual’s responses to questions, particular conclusions about his or her personality can be made.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="maria" changedate="20230522T175519Z" creationid="maria" creationdate="20230522T175519Z">
        <seg>Entonces, teniendo en cuenta tanto el carácter de los dibujos como las respuestas del individuo a las preguntas, se pueden sacar conclusiones particulares sobre su personalidad.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Theo tried to understand the deep-seated melancholy that possessed Vincent which was revealed in the book of their letters to each other, &lt;e0&gt;Dear Theo: The Autobiography of Vincent Van Gogh&lt;/e0&gt; (Van Gogh &amp; Stone, 1995).</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="dinag" changedate="20230523T093226Z" creationid="dinag" creationdate="20230523T093226Z">
        <seg>Theo trató de comprender la profunda melancolía que poseía Vincent, revelada en el libro de cartas que se escribieron el uno al otro,&lt;e0&gt; Querido Theo: La autobiografía de Vincent Van Gogh &lt;/e0&gt; (Van Gogh &amp; Stone, 1995).</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>There is a possibility that Van Gogh’s emotional state can be attributed to bipolar disorder, or manic depression (Gayford, 2008).</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="maria" changedate="20230522T120126Z" creationid="maria" creationdate="20230522T120126Z">
        <seg>Existe la posibilidad de que el estado emocional de Van Gogh pueda atribuirse a un trastorno bipolar o maníaco depresivo (Gayford, 2008).</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>These artists drew and painted many floral still lives, which influenced Van Gogh.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="paula" changedate="20230519T190648Z" creationid="paula" creationdate="20230519T190648Z">
        <seg>Estos artistas dibujaron y pintaron muchos bodegones florales, que influyeron en Van Gogh.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>These civil uprisings broke out through Europe and we’re not always successful, but in France, it led to a new and free country.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="paula" changedate="20230519T181246Z" creationid="paula" creationdate="20230519T181246Z">
        <seg>Estas revueltas civiles estallaron en toda Europa y no siempre tuvieron éxito, pero en Francia dieron lugar a un país nuevo y libre.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>These difficulties weighed heavily on Van Gogh’s.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="maria" changedate="20230522T115015Z" creationid="maria" creationdate="20230522T115015Z">
        <seg>Estas dificultades pesaron mucho sobre Van Gogh.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>These men developed a friendship and were close to each other for they could relate to their inexplicable desire to give a new form to their imaginations as artists and also as people struggling to earn a name in the highly confounding Impressionist art form (de Leeuw, 2006).</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="dinag" changedate="20230523T100009Z" creationid="dinag" creationdate="20230523T100009Z">
        <seg>Estos hombres entablaron amistad y se mostraron cercanos el uno al otro porque podían relacionarse por su inexplicable deseo de dar una nueva forma a su imaginación como artistas y también como personas que luchaban por ganarse un nombre en la muy confusa forma de arte impresionista (de Leeuw, 2006).</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>These were the last days of his life.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="dinag" changedate="20230523T101008Z" creationid="dinag" creationdate="20230523T101008Z">
        <seg>Fueron los últimos días de su vida.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>They also both used the bright yellow color, and other bold, vivid colors to make a lot of floral paintings.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="paula" changedate="20230521T132010Z" creationid="paula" creationdate="20230521T132010Z">
        <seg>Ambos utilizaron también el amarillo brillante y otros colores vivos y atrevidos para hacer muchos cuadros florales.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>They both visited the home of Jean Courbet, a leading painter of that time, who also lived in Provence, to view his work which they admired deeply (Naifeh &amp; Smith, 2011).</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="dinag" changedate="20230523T100203Z" creationid="dinag" creationdate="20230523T100203Z">
        <seg>Ambos visitaron la casa de Jean Courbet, un destacado pintor de la época, que también vivía en Provenza, para ver su obra, que admiraban profundamente (Naifeh y Smith, 2011).</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>They differed in views.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="dinag" changedate="20230511T211445Z" creationid="dinag" creationdate="20230511T211445Z">
        <seg>Ellos diferían en puntos de vista.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>They learned a lot from each other even though their collaboration was not long.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="dinag" changedate="20230511T211345Z" creationid="dinag" creationdate="20230511T211345Z">
        <seg>Aprendieron mucho el uno del otro a pesar de que su colaboración no fue larga.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>They met when they were both living in Paris.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="dinag" changedate="20230523T093857Z" creationid="dinag" creationdate="20230523T093857Z">
        <seg>Se conocieron cuando ambos vivían en París.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>This act of mutilation was thought to be mostly due to the depression he suffered at night and he even tried to give his ear to a prostitute, with whom might he have had a relationship.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="paula" changedate="20230521T160929Z" creationid="paula" creationdate="20230521T160929Z">
        <seg>Se cree que este acto de mutilación se debió sobre todo a la depresión que sufría por las noches e incluso intentó regalar su oreja a una prostituta, con la que podría haber mantenido una relación.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>This activity decreased his hallucinations and paranoid behavior.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="paula" changedate="20230521T164834Z" creationid="paula" creationdate="20230521T164834Z">
        <seg>Esta actividad disminuyó sus alucinaciones y su comportamiento paranóico.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>This added to his troubles.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="OmegaT Aligner" changedate="20230512T004200Z" creationid="OmegaT Aligner" creationdate="20230512T004200Z">
        <seg>Esto agravó sus problemas.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>This affected the financial stability of France.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="maria" changedate="20230522T114943Z" creationid="maria" creationdate="20230522T114943Z">
        <seg>Esto afectó a la estabilidad financiera de Francia.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>This disorder normally affects highly creative individuals who, in most cases, proceed to create ingenious works of art.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="maria" changedate="20230522T120456Z" creationid="maria" creationdate="20230522T120456Z">
        <seg>Este transtorno afecta normalmente a individuos muy creativos que, en la mayoría de los casos, proceden a crear ingeniosas obras de arte.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>This explains why Van Gogh described yellow as his favorite color (Ford, 2014).</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="paula" changedate="20230521T165542Z" creationid="paula" creationdate="20230521T165542Z">
        <seg>Esto explica por qué Van Gogh describió el amarillo como su color favorito (Ford, 2014).</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>This might be is the first historical example of art therapy (Bush, 2014).</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="paula" changedate="20230521T164902Z" creationid="paula" creationdate="20230521T164902Z">
        <seg>Este podría ser el primer ejemplo histórico de arteterapia (Bush, 2014).</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>This painting was the beginning of Vincent’s encounters with nature.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="dinag" changedate="20230523T095113Z" creationid="dinag" creationdate="20230523T095056Z">
        <seg>Este cuadro fue el comienzo de los encuentros de Vincent con la naturaleza.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>This researcher has also been influenced by Van Gogh and wanted to learn more about him.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="OmegaT Aligner" changedate="20230511T161419Z" creationid="OmegaT Aligner" creationdate="20230511T161419Z">
        <seg>Este investigador también ha sido influenciado por Van Gogh y quería aprender más sobre él.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>This was mainly due to dissatisfaction with the political scenario, the desire for freedom of the press, and the need for the people to look after and participate in the law-making and government policies.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="paula" changedate="20230507T200446Z" creationid="paula" creationdate="20230507T200446Z">
        <seg>Esto fue principalmente previsto para el descontento con el escenario político, el deseo de libertad de la presión, y la necesidad de la gente de cuidar y participar al hacer las leyes y las normas del gobierno.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>This was very stressful for Van Gogh and may have been the cause of the many mental problems he suffered during the rest of his life.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="dinag" changedate="20230523T100302Z" creationid="dinag" creationdate="20230523T100302Z">
        <seg>Esto fue muy estresante para Van Gogh y puede haber sido la causa de los muchos problemas mentales que sufrió durante el resto de su vida.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Though he resented leaving the pleasant ambiance of home, it was only when he went to a new middle school, Willem II College in Tilburg, that he encountered Huysmans, a renowned artist from Paris who later helped him to cultivate an interest in art (Naifeh &amp; Smith, 2011).</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="dinag" changedate="20230522T212715Z" creationid="dinag" creationdate="20230522T212715Z">
        <seg>Aunque le molestaba abandonar el agradable ambiente de su hogar, no fue hasta que ingresó en un nuevo centro de enseñanza media, el Colegio Willem II de Tilburg, cuando conoció a Huysmans, un renombrado artista de París que más tarde le ayudó a cultivar su interés por el arte (Naifeh &amp; Smith, 2011).</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Throughout this thesis, the researcher will review Vincent Van Gogh’s talent.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="OmegaT Aligner" changedate="20230511T161419Z" creationid="OmegaT Aligner" creationdate="20230511T161419Z">
        <seg>A lo largo de esta tesis, el investigador repasará el talento de Vincent Van Gogh.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Thujone is present in Absinthe which might have increased Vincent Van Gogh’s mental illness, depression, anxiety, and his epilepsy.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="paula" changedate="20230521T165741Z" creationid="paula" creationdate="20230521T165741Z">
        <seg>La tuyona está presente en la absenta, lo que podría haber agravado las enfermedades mentales, la depresión, la ansiedad y la epilepsia de Vincent Van Gogh.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Thujone poisoning</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="paula" changedate="20230521T165825Z" creationid="paula" creationdate="20230521T165623Z">
        <seg>Intoxicación por tujona</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Thus the understanding of bipolar disorder or maniac depressive disorder can provide a great source of understanding about Vincent Van Gogh’s life (Hulsker &amp; Miller, 1990).</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="paula" changedate="20230521T165211Z" creationid="paula" creationdate="20230521T165211Z">
        <seg>Así, la comprensión del trastorno bipolar o trastorno maníaco depresivo puede proporcionar una gran fuente de comprensión sobre la vida de Vincent Van Gogh (Hulsker &amp; Miller, 1990).</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>To conclude, Vincent van Gogh’s paintings are full of vivid positive and dark negative emotions, which often reflect the painter’s state of mind.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="maria" changedate="20230511T153602Z" creationid="maria" creationdate="20230511T153602Z">
        <seg>Para concluir, los cuadros de Vicent van Gogh están llenos de emociones alegres positivas, y oscuras negativas, que a menudo refleja los estados de ánimo del pintor.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>To cope with the painful outcomes of epilepsy and depression, Van Gogh developed a habit to drink absinthe, a drink that was cheap and rather toxic.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="paula" changedate="20230521T165656Z" creationid="paula" creationdate="20230521T165656Z">
        <seg>Para hacer frente a las dolorosas consecuencias de la epilepsia y la depresión, Van Gogh adquirió el hábito de beber absenta, una bebida barata y bastante tóxica.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Van Gogh and Gauguin are known as two of the most influential artists of their era.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="dinag" changedate="20230511T211256Z" creationid="dinag" creationdate="20230511T211256Z">
        <seg>Van Gogh y Gauguin ambos son conocidos como los artistas más influyentes de su era.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Van Gogh and Gauguin even found an art school together but it did not work out as expected.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="dinag" changedate="20230523T100056Z" creationid="dinag" creationdate="20230523T100056Z">
        <seg>Van Gogh y Gauguin incluso fundaron juntos una escuela de arte, pero no funcionó como se esperaba.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Van Gogh had a difficult childhood this was attributed to his lack of proper socialization in early childhood.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="OmegaT Aligner" changedate="20230512T004200Z" creationid="OmegaT Aligner" creationdate="20230512T004200Z">
        <seg>Van Gogh tuvo una infancia difícil, atribuida a su falta de socialización en la primera infancia.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Van Gogh had no success in the choice of careers that had been laid out for him by his parents.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="OmegaT Aligner" changedate="20230512T004200Z" creationid="OmegaT Aligner" creationdate="20230512T004200Z">
        <seg>Van Gogh no tuvo éxito en la elección de carreras que le habían planteado sus padres.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Van Gogh himself has mentioned that Gauguin liked sunflowers, so he was painting them while missing his friend, suffering from loneliness and isolation.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="OmegaT Aligner" changedate="20230512T004200Z" creationid="OmegaT Aligner" creationdate="20230512T004200Z">
        <seg>El propio Van Gogh ha mencionado que a Gauguin le gustaban los girasoles, así que los pintaba mientras echaba de menos a su amigo, aquejado de soledad y aislamiento.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Van Gogh is thought to have suffered from a combination of physical and mental disorders.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="dinag" changedate="20230522T211328Z" creationid="dinag" creationdate="20230522T211328Z">
        <seg>Se cree que Van Gogh sufría una combinación de trastornos físicos y mentales.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Van Gogh started to be disconnected from his family at a very young age due to his failure to perform successfully in the career fields they chose for him such as teaching, religion, and sales (Butterfield, 2011).</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="paula" changedate="20230507T194459Z" creationid="paula" creationdate="20230507T192232Z">
        <seg>Van Gogh dejó de tener relación con su familia a una edad muy temprana debido a su fracaso de realizar exitosamente una carrera en el campo que ellos habían escogido para él, como la enseñanza, la religión y las ventas (Butterfield, 2011).</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Van Gogh suffered from some severe active mental disorders which are now thought to have been periods of depression which led him to risky behaviors such as smoking, drinking, trying to cut off his ear, and finally suicide.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="paula" changedate="20230521T153139Z" creationid="paula" creationdate="20230521T153139Z">
        <seg>Van Gogh padeció algunos trastornos mentales activos graves que ahora se cree que fueron periodos de depresión que le llevaron a comportamientos arriesgados como fumar, beber, intentar cortarse una oreja y, finalmente, al suicidio.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Van Gogh tried his luck in selling art, preaching, and book-keeping.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="OmegaT Aligner" changedate="20230512T004200Z" creationid="OmegaT Aligner" creationdate="20230512T004200Z">
        <seg>Van Gogh probó suerte vendiendo arte, predicando y llevando la contabilidad.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Van Gogh was born during the Franco-Prussian War which took a toll on the economy of France.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="maria" changedate="20230522T114803Z" creationid="maria" creationdate="20230522T114803Z">
        <seg>Van Gogh nació durante la guerra franco-prusiana, que afectó a la economía de Francia.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Van Gogh was diagnosed with a brain lesion.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="paula" changedate="20230521T165420Z" creationid="paula" creationdate="20230521T165420Z">
        <seg>A Van Gogh le diagnostican una lesión cerebral.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Van Gogh was influenced by the style of Rubens and the Japanese still life which he traveled to see in Antwerp (Naifeh &amp; Smith, 2011).</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="dinag" changedate="20230522T212045Z" creationid="dinag" creationdate="20230522T212045Z">
        <seg>Van Gogh se vio influenciado por el estilo de Rubens y los bodegones japoneses que viajó a ver a Amberes (Naifeh y Smith, 2011).</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Van Gogh was later found by local police almost bleeding to death (Heenk, 2013).</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="paula" changedate="20230521T161026Z" creationid="paula" creationdate="20230521T161026Z">
        <seg>Más tarde, la policía local encontró a Van Gogh casi desangrándose (Heenk, 2013).</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Van Gogh “saw himself as wrongly convicted, not ill” (Charles, 2014, p.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="maria" changedate="20230511T155331Z" creationid="maria" creationdate="20230511T155331Z">
        <seg>Van Gogh “Lo ví como erróneamente condenado, no enfermo” (Charles, 2014, p.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Van Gogh’s Mental Illness: Was it Depression?</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="paula" changedate="20230521T152850Z" creationid="paula" creationdate="20230521T152850Z">
        <seg>La enfermedad mental de Van Gogh: ¿Fue depresión?</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Van Gogh’s last words were directed for his brother, as he said “The sadness will last forever” (Van Gogh, 2003, p.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="dinag" changedate="20230523T093518Z" creationid="dinag" creationdate="20230523T093518Z">
        <seg>Las últimas palabras de Van Gogh iban dirigidas a su hermano, ya que dijo: "La tristeza durará para siempre" (Van Gogh, 2003, p.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Van Gogh’s life was very short – he died at 37 years old, after creating more than 900 paintings and 1000 other works of art.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="dinag" changedate="20230523T101249Z" creationid="dinag" creationdate="20230523T101249Z">
        <seg>La vida de Van Gogh fue muy corta: murió a los 37 años, después de haber creado más de 900 cuadros y otras 1.000 obras de arte.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Van Gogh’s mind was occupied by beauty while he practiced painting in Belgium.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="dinag" changedate="20230522T211916Z" creationid="dinag" creationdate="20230522T211916Z">
        <seg>La mente de Van Gogh estaba ocupada por la belleza mientras practicaba la pintura en Bélgica.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Van Gogh’s sympathy towards the lower class people (peasants, miners, prostitutes) resulted in conflicts with his family but made a positive impact on his art.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="paula" changedate="20230519T183149Z" creationid="paula" creationdate="20230519T183149Z">
        <seg>La simpatía de Van Gogh hacia la gente de clase baja (campesinos, mineros, prostitutas) dio como resultado conflictos con su familia, pero tuvo un gran impacto en su arte.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Various incidents demonstrate Vincent Van Gogh’s depression:</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="paula" changedate="20230521T153706Z" creationid="paula" creationdate="20230521T153706Z">
        <seg>Varios incidentes demuestran la depresión de Vincent Van Gogh:</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Vincent Van Gogh had a miserable childhood and was described as unstable with emotional problems.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="dinag" changedate="20230511T161910Z" creationid="OmegaT Aligner" creationdate="20230511T161419Z">
        <seg>Vincent Van Gogh tuvo una infancia desafortunada y fue descrito como inestable y con problemas emocionales.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Vincent Van Gogh himself thought that he might be suffering from epilepsy.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="paula" changedate="20230521T165333Z" creationid="paula" creationdate="20230521T165333Z">
        <seg>El propio Vincent Van Gogh pensó que podía padecer epilepsia.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Vincent Van Gogh made a significant influence on the art of the 20th century.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="OmegaT Aligner" changedate="20230511T161419Z" creationid="OmegaT Aligner" creationdate="20230511T161419Z">
        <seg>Vincent Van Gogh ejerció una influencia significativa en el arte del siglo XX.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Vincent Van Gogh was a prolific artist in the 19th century.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="OmegaT Aligner" changedate="20230512T004200Z" creationid="OmegaT Aligner" creationdate="20230512T004200Z">
        <seg>Vincent Van Gogh fue un prolífico artista del siglo XIX.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Vincent Van Gogh was extremely close to his brother Theo, whom he believed to be his confidante.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="dinag" changedate="20230523T092549Z" creationid="dinag" creationdate="20230523T092549Z">
        <seg>Vincent Van Gogh estaba muy unido a su hermano Theo, al que consideraba su confidente.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Vincent Van Gogh’s two strongest relationships seem to have been with his brother, Theo, and Paul Gauguin, a contemporary artist.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="dinag" changedate="20230511T211158Z" creationid="dinag" creationdate="20230511T211158Z">
        <seg>Las dos relaciones más cercanas de Vincent Van Gogh parece que fueron con su hermano, Theo, y con Paul Gauguin, un artista contemporáneo.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Vincent Willem Van Gogh, usually known as Van Gogh&lt;s0&gt;, &lt;/s0&gt;was born in Groot-Zundert, Holland, on March 30, 1853.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="dinag" changedate="20230522T212452Z" creationid="dinag" creationdate="20230522T212452Z">
        <seg>Vincent Willem Van Gogh, normalmente conocido como Van Gogh&lt;s0&gt;,&lt;/s0&gt;nació en Groot-Zundert, Holanda, el 30 de marzo de 1853</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Vincent seems to have been affected mentally by the fact that his father was a pastor, making him a mostly unstable child with emotional problems.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="dinag" changedate="20230511T212000Z" creationid="dinag" creationdate="20230511T212000Z">
        <seg>Vincent parece haber sido afectado psicológicamente por el hecho de que su padre era un pastor, convirtiéndole en un nino inestable con problemas emocionales.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Vincent van Gogh has had a complicated childhood, and the hardships of his later life worsened his mental state.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="maria" changedate="20230511T154221Z" creationid="maria" creationdate="20230511T154221Z">
        <seg>Vincent van Gogh tuvo una infancia complicada, y las dificultades de su vida posterior empeoraron su estado mental.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>When Van Gogh moved in with his brother Theo in Paris in March 1886 he met Henri de Toulouse Lautrec in Cormon’s studio where Lautrec drew Van Gogh’s painting in pastel.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="paula" changedate="20230519T184047Z" creationid="paula" creationdate="20230519T184047Z">
        <seg>Cuando Van Gogh se traslada a vivir con su hermano Theo a París en marzo de 1886, conoce a Henri de Toulouse Lautrec en el estudio de Cormon, donde Lautrec dibuja al pastel el cuadro de Van Gogh.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>When a person finishes the task, he or she is asked questions about the pictures.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="maria" changedate="20230522T174842Z" creationid="maria" creationdate="20230522T174842Z">
        <seg>Cuando una persona termina la tarea, se le hacen preguntas sobre los dibujos.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Where Gauguin supported abstract art, Vincent Van Gogh supported the reality of the world.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="dinag" changedate="20230511T211600Z" creationid="dinag" creationdate="20230511T211600Z">
        <seg>Mientras Gauguin apoyaba el arte abstracto, Vincent Van Gogh apoyaba el realismo del mundo.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Working as a missionary, Van Gogh often engaged in communication with the poorest population and happened to adopt their worldview starting to believe that religion was irrelevant to reality (Butterfield, 2011).</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="paula" changedate="20230507T192914Z" creationid="paula" creationdate="20230507T192914Z">
        <seg>Trabajando como misionero, Van Gogh a menudo se involucró en la comunicación con la población más pobre y debido a ello adoptó su visión del resto del mundo, empezando por creer que la religión era irrelevante a la realidad (Butterfield, 2011).</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>Working on a painting provided him some relief, the one that therapy could provide.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="OmegaT Aligner" changedate="20230512T004200Z" creationid="OmegaT Aligner" creationdate="20230512T004200Z">
        <seg>Trabajar en un cuadro le proporcionaba cierto alivio, el que podía proporcionar la terapia.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>You may draw any kind of house you like, it will not be counted against you.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="maria" changedate="20230522T121800Z" creationid="maria" creationdate="20230522T121800Z">
        <seg>Puede dibujar el tipo de casa que quiera, no se tendrá en cuenta.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>perceived as a reticent child and while he attended the Zundert village school, he was taught by a Catholic tutor along with 200 other students.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="dinag" changedate="20230522T212615Z" creationid="dinag" creationdate="20230522T212615Z">
        <seg>percibido como un niño reticente y, mientras asistió a la escuela del pueblo de Zundert, recibió clases de un tutor católico junto con otros 200 alumnos.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
    <tu>
      <tuv lang="en">
        <seg>“Sunflowers” was created in one of the hardest periods of Van Gogh’s life.</seg>
      </tuv>
      <tuv lang="es-ES" changeid="maria" changedate="20230512T005431Z" creationid="OmegaT Aligner" creationdate="20230512T004200Z">
        <seg>"Los Girasoles" fue creado en uno de los periodos más duros de la vida de Van Gogh.</seg>
      </tuv>
    </tu>
<!-- Alternative translations -->
  </body>
</tmx>
